Mousa Shaer (AKA Rony Shaer)

ronyshaer96@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rony-shaer-593830197

Summary

EX-Production engineer @ Meta Platforms.

My job was to collaborate with different engineering teams & partners to champion the Reliability, Scalability, Performance, and Security posture of production services.

Throughout my journey @ meta I was exposed to different technologies, and gained a lot of experience in building and maintaining huge platforms with billions of users.

Career highlights:

• Designing & building a CI/CD pipeline:

This project aimed to automate the integration & deployment of different services.

The project saved a lot of manual work for our team and enable them to invest more time in developing and improving company's products.

· Building infrastructure:

Played and important role in building and maintaining NOVI infrastructure, Built of multi services (Java, Nodejs, Python) on the AWS cloud.

Automation:

Tests became one click away, support E2E test on the code changes. This project saved our team a lot of time, instead of gathering all the information needed and following a documentation to run the test, simply trigger the button and you're set to go!

· Analyzer:

Analyzer integrated to alerts, once an alert is fired the analyzer is triggered and gather data from different resources & finally displays what could have went wrong.

Skills:

- Programming languages:
- Python
- Java
- C
- C++
- PHP
- · Ability to learn new languages.
- Experience in platforms & softwares:
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Helm
- CircleCI

- Terraform
- Nginx
- Experienced in Cloud Computing Platform (AWS) services:
- EKS
- EC2
- RDS
- ECR
- S3
- Secret Manager
- Experienced in maintaining and working with databases:
- NRD- MongoDB
- RD Mysql
- · Very well understanding of networking protocols.
- Good understanding in web developments:
- Fundamentals of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- · Knowledge of frameworks like React.js

Experience

Production Engineer

Meta

Mar 2021 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

Production Engineering Intern

Meta

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020 (4 months)

Education



Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2016 - 2021

Skills

Scalability • Solving hard problems in systems serving billions of people. • Systems Engineering • Software Design • Ability to build strong relationships with partners.